primarygames.com 2014-12-19

# Privacy Policy - PrimaryGames - Play Free Kids Games Online

**Privacy Policy**

#### Effective: September 3, 2013

**PrimaryGames.com** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. PrimaryGames is intended to provide fun and educational resources for kids and teens to use under the guidance of their parents and teachers. As required by The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), we provide this privacy policy to inform parents and legal guardians (collectively, “Parents”) about our privacy practices on our site www.primarygames.com.

PrimaryGames.com has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy and Children’s Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers information collected on our site [www.primarygames.com](http://www.primarygames.com/) and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications, mobile sites, or downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@primarygames.com](mailto:privacy@primarygames.com) .  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

#### Information Automatically Logged

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information. We use this information to help us design a website that is targeted to the interests of our visitors. We do not tie any personal information to your IP address.

#### Cookies

PrimaryGames uses cookies to track game progress and level completion. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

#### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ or our third party tracking utility partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

#### Advertisers

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. In response to the new COPPA rules, PrimaryGames.com has opted out of behaviorally targeted ads from all of our advertising networks, and instead only shows contextually-based ads or other carefully-selected ads which are not based on a user's browsing behavior.

We have asked all of our advertising networks to turn off all behaviorally targeted ads that would track a user or attempt to create a profile on any of our users. We have also alerted our advertising agencies that a portion of our audience is "under 13" and that they need to adhere to all COPPA rules and regulations. PrimaryGames does not run behaviorally targeted ads, but, if you want to opt out of these on other websites that do, you can opt out here: <http://www.iab.net/privacymatters/>

In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique “cookie” or web beacon on your browser.

You can view the privacy policies for each ad company by following the links below:

BURST! Media: <http://www.burstmedia.com/privacy.html>

Advertising.com: <http://advertising.aol.com/privacy>

ValueClick: <https://www.valueclickmedia.com/about/privacy>

24-7 Real Media: <http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html>

Tribal Fusion: <http://exponential.com/our-company/privacy/>

Casale Media: <http://www.casalemedia.com/privacy.html>

Genome from Yahoo!: <http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/adserving/>

Google Adsense: <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>

CPMStar: <http://www.cpmstar.com/privacyPolicy.html>

Viacom Media Network Tribes: <http://www.viacom.com/privacypolicy/Pages/default.aspx>

Optimatic: <http://www.optimatic.com/dev.optimatic.com/Files/privacy.htm>

Adify: <http://www.adify.com/privacy-policy>

Glam Media: <http://www.glammedia.com/about_glam/legal/privacy-security/>

Commission Junction: <http://www.cj.com/legal/privacy_web_user.html>

Linkshare: <http://www.linkshare.com/legal/privacy/>

Amazon: <http://www.amazon.com/privacy>

Games Banner Network: <http://gamesbannernet.com/TOS.html>

Driver Digital: <http://www.driverdigital.com/privacy>

#### Analytics

PrimaryGames.com uses third-party analytics software to provide us with information regarding the usage of the Website. The information we receive from such third-party analytics software is not Personal Information attributable to any user but rather information that is aggregated by the software so that we can track such things as how many users we have of the Website on a daily, weekly or monthly basis, what Website content or features our users are frequenting and the general geographic locations of our users.

To opt-out from this type of tracking, please use the links below:  
Google Analytics: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
Quantcast: <https://www.quantcast.com/company/opt-out/>

#### External Links

This site contains links to other sites. **PrimaryGames.com** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to the information collected on this Site.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Children's Guidelines

We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children:

We will NOT collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent.

When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, the virtual worlds we partner with will only use the online contact information (such as email) to: 

  1. Respond directly to the child's request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes. Once we have responded to such request we will delete the information provided immediately.

  2. Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification.

  3. Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not used to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity.

We will provide you with a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected on the site, for instance when you send a post card, we may collect your name, email address and recipient’s name and email address. We do not store this information for any purpose.

#### E-Cards and Postcards

We hope you and your children enjoy our E-cards together. The information you submit is for your card only. It appears on your computer screen for your use and is deleted when the email card activity is completed. Email cards sent via e-mail to your selected recipient(s) are automatically deleted from our files 21 days after you send them. You must be 13 years or older to submit information. Parents, please help your child fill out the postcard forms. When sending a postcard for the first time, we require users to specify for their age. Any users who identify themselves as under 13 will be blocked from using our postcard service. We use persistent cookies to remember whether or not the user is over the age of 13.

#### Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. The only information we collect from you prior to allowing your use of the tell a friend feature that is ran by a third party social media feature is your age to determine whether or not you are able to use this feature.

#### Third Party Sharing

We will share your personal information only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as providing customer support or content management. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified by prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

#### Access to Personal Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at privacy@primarygames.com. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information as needed to provide you services. If you wish to request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at the email address provided above. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Age Restricted Activities

Most of the activities and features on PrimaryGames.com are able to be enjoyed by all ages. There a minor few that require the user to be 13 years or older. On these pages, we ask users to specify their age. Any users who identify themselves as under 13 will be blocked from using these pages or services. We use cookies to remember whether or not the user is over the age of 13 in order to tailor their experience while using PrimaryGames.com.

#### Virtual Worlds

We feature several Virtual Worlds for children from third-party partner web sites on PrimaryGames.com. All information collected while interacting with each world is collected by the Company that owns and maintains that particular world. Please refer to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions for each individual Virtual World. We have provided links to each world's Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions on the game's web page. Questions regarding each world should be directed to the appropriate party and contact links for each game can be found on the game's web page.

#### Changes in this Privacy Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

If we make material changes to how we use personal information collected from children under 13, we will notify parents by e-mail (if possible), or by means of a notice on this Site in order to obtain verifiable consent for the new uses of the child's personal information.

#### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

PrimaryGames, Inc.  
8947 Hollymeade Drive  
Lorton, VA 22079  
(703) 493-8568
